《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
这家伙不简单
There's something about this guy.
他知道我们要去哪 看穿我的心思
He knows where we're going, what we're thinking.
他迟早会知道犹他州的钱
It's a matter of time before he finds out about the money in Utah...
还有我们逃到墨西哥的方法 所有事物
...and our way into Mexico, everything.
侦讯时可以请律师在场陪同
You can have an attorney present during questioning.
卡洛琳，警方把她带走了 我当然会盯住她
Caroline, they're taking her in. Of course. I'll keep an eye on her.
是我做的，爸
I did it, Dad.
照我的话去做
Just do as you're told.
否则后果对我们 都会有很大的影响
Otherwise, there will be consequences that will affect us all.
我爸是空军上校
My dad's an Air Force colonel.
我告诉他我要和男生同住 而且又对他有好感时
When I told him I was staying in a hotel with a guy that I maybe sort of liked...
他气死了
...he lost it.
-你来干嘛？犸丽在哪？ -她现在是我的
- What're you doing here? Where's Maricruz? - She's with me.
-告诉我她在哪里？ -费南多，别激动
- Just tell me where she is. - Hey, Fernando, slow down, man.
我原本要告诉你的 他们去赌城结婚了
I was trying to tell you the wedding is in Vegas.
-死者是哪一个？ -可能是史柯菲
- So which one of them it was it? - Might be scofield.
他哥哥的尸体应该也在里面
Probably gonna find his brother in there too.
-目的地是哪里，先生？ -犹他州
- Where to, sir? - Utah.
（150号公路 犹他州Q湖城东方75里）
今早伊利诺州官方 发布了逃犯的最新进展
This morning, authorities in Illinois issued an update on the escaped convicts,,,
截至目前为止 他们被称为福克斯河八人帮
,,, known, until now, as the Fox River Eight,
芝加哥黑帮老大约翰亚布兹
chicago mob boss John Abruzzi,,,
昨晚在华盛顿特区的 汽车旅馆外遭击毙
,,, was gunned down outside a Washington, D, c, motel last night,,,
一切要归功于线人的密告
,,, after investigators received a tip from an informant,
其余七名逃犯依然在逃 并且被认定为相当危险
The other seven escapees are still at large and considered dangerous,
一名佛州男子遭通缉K
A Florida man wanted in...
我没料到亚布兹会是第一个
I didn't think Abruzzi'd be the first to eat it.
我有预感之后会惊奇不断
I have a feeling we're in for lots of surprises.
新闻说七名逃犯在逃 诈死似乎不管用
They said seven are still out there. So much for faking our deaths.
我争取到一些时间 这才是重点
I bought us some time. That's what counts.
-还有多远？ -七、八十里
- How much further? - Seventy, 80 miles.
很好，下午应该 就能抵达开开牧场
Means we should be hitting Double-K Ranch by this afternoon.
或是继续开去救罗杰 再去巴拿马
We could keep driving, pick up L.J. And hit Panama.
我们不能去巴拿马，哪都不能去 没有钱我们什么事都做不了
We can't hit Panama. We can't hit anything. We can't do anything without the money.
我们得找到查理藏的钱
We need to find Charles' stash.
我知道其他人也有此打算
I know some other guys who are thinking the same thing.
钱就埋在犹他州图尔
The money is buried under a silo at the Double-K Ranch...
开开牧场的地窖底下 里面有五百万美金
...just outside of Tooele, Utah. There's $5 million there.
（绿河市，怀俄明州）
查票
Tickets.
我在昔安的时候 把车票从背包拉出来
You know, when I was in Cheyenne, I pulled my ticket out of the bag.
结果破成两半 车票另一半现在不见了
It tore in half, and I have no idea what happened to the other part.
-车站没有帮你换？ -没有
- They didn't issue you a replacement? - No.
我记得那位小姐叫雪莉
The young lady, I think her name was sherry...
她说这一半可以用 因为上面有条码
...she actually said that this half was okay because the barcode was on it.
你需要完整的车票
Well, you really need the whole ticket.
我当初就是这么跟她说的
This is exactly what I was trying to avoid.
她说这样没关系，因为K
She said everything would be fine because...
没关系，现在没事
That's okay. It'll do for now.
但请你到普洛伏时 一定要换张新车票
But make sure you ask for a replacement when you get to Provo.
我一定会的，谢谢
I definitely will. Thank you.
-总是有事情会发生 -对啊
- It's always something, huh? - Oh, God, I know.
（科罗拉多州，梅克）
（科罗拉多与犹他州边界10里处）
（汽车旅馆）
我不想回家
I don't wanna go home.
我希望能一路开下去
I wish we could keep driving.
你爸爸听了一定会很不高兴
I don't think your pops will be down for that.
这样不是很好玩吗？
Wouldn't it be fun?
我们可以去夏威夷
We could go to Hawaii.
-开车到不了夏威夷 -我知道
- No, you can't drive to Hawaii. - I know.
我知道
I know.
我只是想想而已
I'm just saying, I wish.
-不要开门，他们会走掉 -我去看是谁
- No, don't get it. They'll leave. - Just let me see who it is.
是警察
It's a cop.
不要开K
No, no, no.
抱歉打扰你，小姐 请问你见过这个人吗？
Sorry to disturb you, ma'am. Have you happened to see this person?
片名：越狱风云
剧名：第1213页地图
昨晚有人通报，说他出现在附近
Last night, we got a few phone calls that he was spotted in the area.
我们才会挨家挨户问
So we're going door to door.
你们为何要找他？
Why are you looking for him?
他几天前逃出 伊利诺州的一处监狱
He escaped from prison in Illinois a couple of days ago.
你有见过他吗？
Have you seen him?
没有
No.
我没有见过他
He doesn't look familiar.
你确定？
Are you sure?
对，我确定
Yeah, I'm sure.
好，谢谢你拨空
All right. Thanks for your time.
这件事不是你想像中的那样
This ain't... This is not what you think, all right?
相信我，听我说，好吗？
Look, trust me. Just listen, okay?
我只是偷了一张棒球卡 我跟其他坏人不一样
All I did was steal a baseball card, okay? I'm not like those other fools up in there.
我要去散步，好吗？
I'm gonna go for a walk, okay?
我把车钥匙留下
I'm gonna leave my keys right here.
等我回来的时候 我的车子会消失
And when I come back, my car will be gone.
我相信几小时后 他们会找到它
I'm sure in a few hours, they'll find it somewhere...
被弃置在某处
...abandoned.
等等K
Wait, wait.
我真希望情况不是这样
I wish it could be different.
我得走了
I have to go.
-图力 -我想是念“图尔”
- Tooele. - I think it's "Tooele."
-好一个小镇 -小对我们有利
- Hell of a town. - Small is good.
代表牧场会很好找
Means the ranch'll be easier to find.
我们只要拿到钱
All we gotta do is get that money...
-在日落前离开这里 -对
...and be out of here by nightfall. - Nice.
（FBI分局 伊利诺州芝加哥）
长官，车祸的土壤化验出炉了
Oh, sir. Soil tests came back from scofield's crash.
虽然你已经不需要更多证据 不过他真的大费周章准备
Not that you need any more proof, but he really went out of his way this time.
你还有什么消息？
What else do you have?
内布拉斯加有男子遭搭便车者 猛烈攻击，面貌与包威吻合
A man was assaulted in Nebraska by a hitchhiker matching Bagwell's description.
他在80号州际公路往西走 奥马哈市正准备照片指证
He was headed west on the l-80. Omaha's putting together a photo lineup.
有史柯菲的线索吗？
What do you have on scofield?
任何人有史柯菲的消息吗？
What does anybody have on scofield?
我们从河底捞出来的硬碟 有些线索
I've got some results from his hard drive. The one recovered from the river.
我们用区段编辑器 修复主开机区，然后K
We were able to use the sector editor to restore the master boot. So from that...
我不管修复的方式，你查到什么？
I don't care how you did it. What do you have?
缓冲记忆体半数以上的内容 约百分之60
More than half the contents of the buffer. About 60 percent.
-资料看起来没有头绪 -全部列印出来，放到我的桌上
- It looks pretty random. - Print it up, all of it. I want it on my desk.
你猜怎么着？
Well, guess what.
开开牧场没有登记在电话簿上
No listing for a Double-K Ranch.
抱歉，你知道开开牧场在哪里吗？
Excuse me. You know where I might find the Double-K Ranch?
-什么名字？ -开开牧场
- What'd you call it? - Double-K Ranch.
-不知道 -你是这里人吗？
- No. - You from around here?
对，土生土长
Yeah. Born and raised.
这里没有这牧场
There's no double nothing.
太好了，谢谢
Great. Thank you.
看来威莫兰 用尽最后一口气摆了你一道
Looks like Westmoreland spent his last breath blowing smoke up your ass.
只有一个方法能证实
There's one way to find out.
每个郡都有地产纪录
The county keeps property records.
每块土地都有记载面积的地图 这是公开纪录
Every plot is mapped out with dimensions. It's public record.
但如果这里有估税员办公室
But if there is a tax assessor's office here...
东西一定在那里
...it's gonna be in there.
市政大楼
In the municipal building.
里面有很多警察，麦可
Lot of cops in there, Michael.
-警局 -有人K
- Dispatch, - Someone,,,,
今天早上偷了我的车，我在80号 公路附近的莲花汽车旅馆
Someone stole my car this morning, I'm at the Lotus Motel off Interstate 80,
-你有看见偷车贼吗？ -没有，我出去散步
- Did you see who took it? - No, I went out for a walk,
-回来车就不见了 -今天早上？为何现在才报警？
- And when I came back, it was gone, - This morning? Why didn't you call before?
我不知道
I don't know,
（啊哈）
（伊利诺州，芝加哥）
-凯勒曼先生 -金先生
- Mr. Kellerman. - Mr. Kim.
-没想到你会出现在芝加哥 -只是来查看进展
- Surprised to see you in Chicago. - Just looking for updates.
莎拉丹奎迪，在我的掌握之中
Sara Tancredi. I'm on it.
-你的时间该用来跟踪她吗？ -没错
- Is pursuing her the best use of your time? - It is.
她和史柯菲有连络 他昨天打给她时我在场
She's in contact with scofield. I was there when he called yesterday.
只要跟着她就能找到他 他能引导我们找到柏劳
We stay with her, she takes us right to him, he takes us to Burrows.
好
All right.
-如果你有自信的话 -我是有
- Lf you're that confident. - I am.
-我会通知总统 -我直接和总统联络
- I'll let the president know. - I contact the president directly.
由我和她连络
I'll contact her.
有消息向我回报
Keep me posted.
（莎拉丹奎迪小姐）
（736-339-8687）
If you wanna restore dignity, you need to take action,
若想要找回尊严 就必须付诸行动
赎罪不光是说句道歉就好
Making amends requires much more than saying, "I'm sorry,"
而是学习改变
It means learning to change.
道歉只是第一步骤
The apology's just the first step.
最重要的一点是 当你向人道歉时
The most important thing is that you display honesty...
必须展现诚意 勇气以及同理心
...courage and compassion when you extend your apologies.
宽恕是必须努力去争取的
You need to earn your forgiveness.
我们周五再深入讨论
We'll talk about it more on Friday.
-我有一个好主意 -什么？
- I got a great idea. - What's that?
既然你这么爱吃 超市买的三流蓝莓派
Since you are such a fan of lame, store-bought blueberry pie...
今晚我烤真正的派给你吃 口味任选
...I'm gonna bake you a real pie of your choice tonight.
我没办法
I can't.
我现在应该只能和心理医生见面
I really don't need to be seeing anyone right now who isn't my therapist.
我最近也像个隐士
I've been a hermit lately too.
我的男友丹尼尔出差去了
My partner Daniel's away on business.
每天晚上 我只能独自在家里发呆
I've been sitting around every night by myself.
真的很可悲
Kind of pathetic.
对不起，我以为你是要K
I'm so sorry. I thought you meant...
我以为K
I thought...
-你请我吃派K -不是的
- The pie... - oh, no.
-我是说真的 -派？
- No, I was really talking about... - Pie?
对，真的蓝莓派 我们一起烤
Yeah, actual blueberries. Like we'd make pie and watch Fried Green Tomatoes.
然后看《油炸绿蕃茄》
- I get it. I get it. - I'm the best ex-junkie cook in this town.
-我懂了K -我是这一带厨艺最好的前毒虫
谢谢，我得K打扫我的公寓
Thank you. I just... I gotta clean my apartment.
里面脏乱不堪 我知道听起来很像借口
It's disgusting. I realize that sounds like an excuse.
-但这是真的 -不K没关系
- It's not. - No, no, no, I get it.
你去做你的事吧
You do what you gotta do.
祝你晚安
Have a good night.
你愿意外送吗？
You deliver?
（迪比库柏依然在逃）
新的一批资料
Next batch.
放在桌上就好
Just put it on the desk.
-这些资料有意义吗？ -不知道，待会再问
- Any of this stuff mean anything? - I don't know. Ask me later.
你认为他是天才还是疯子？
Is he a genius or a whack job?
我们派出上百位探员 就是答案了
We answered that when we assigned 100 agents.
请你去拿剩下来的资料好吗？
So why don't you go get me the rest of it?
这回答你满意吗？
Does that work for you?
（自助服务）
真是太幸运了
Alackaday.
我找到一个好帮手
I just found me an in-betweener.
-你急着上哪去？ -不干你的事
- Where you going in such a hurry? - None of your beeswax, yo.
我知道你要去哪
I know where.
那晚在场的人都要去同一个地方
The same place as every other man that was in that room that night.
所有人都会来开开牧场大团圆
They all coming around here for a big family reunion at the Ku Klux Ranch.
他们迟早会来的
If they ain't here already.
这里的乡巴佬 没一个听过开开牧场
There ain't no fool in this town ever heard of the Double-K Ranch.
看来你被骗了 的确有个开开牧场
It seems like you been misinformed. There is a Double-K.
只是看谁先找到 我们全员会在图尔团聚
It's just a matter of who gets there first. The stars are gonna collide in Tooele.
你会需要我的帮忙
You'll need me on your side.
这里不是监狱好吗？ 我不需要你K
This ain't Fox River, all right? I don't need any...
如你所见
As you can see...
我需要你
...I need you.
把你的脏手拿开，你这变态
Get your grubby paws off me, you freak.
我才不要帮你做苦力
I ain't your ditch digger.
你对我没有用处
I don't need nothing from you.
一点用也没有
I don't need nothing.
可能会有用
You might.
如果你知道从何着手的话
If a man knew where he was supposed to be looking...
（拉斯维加斯100里外 内华达州）
你好
Hi,
请问今天有举办赫特阿维拉 和犸丽戴卡度的婚礼吗？
Are you having the Hector Avila and Maricruz Delgado wedding today?
是阿维拉，没有？谢谢
Avila. No? Thanks.
（拉斯维加斯教堂）
请问今天有举办赫特阿维拉 和犸丽戴卡度的婚礼吗？
Hi. Are you having the Hector Avila and Maricruz Delgado wedding today?
阿维拉
Avila.
戴卡度
Delgado.
真的？
Really?
几点？
When?
保持冷静，我们十分钟后就离开
Stay calm. We'll be out of here in 10 minutes.
一个一个来
One at a time.
安全、请退后
Clear. Back up.
你有戴手表吗？
You wearing a watch?
有
Yeah.
今天的天气不错
Nice day.
谢谢
Thanks.
这就是我们要找的 每一块地的地图
This is exactly what we need. It's a map of every parcel of land.
地形图、建筑物，应有尽有
Topography, buildings, everything.
（卡尔库库辛）
Karl Kokosing. Double-K.
卡尔库库辛，缩写KK
我不喜欢那个人看我们的眼神
I don't like the way this guy's looking at us.
（1213）
1213页
Twelve-thirteen.
1213页在哪里？
Where's 1213?
-席法特，我有事找你 -快点，我们得马上走
- Hey, seifert. I need to speak with you. - Come on, man. We gotta roll now.
-席法特 -快，找到地图了吗？
- Hey, seifert. - Come on. You got the map?
没有
No.
有人拿走了
Someone else does.
有人抢先我们一步 这是唯一的解释
Someone got here before us. It's the only explanation.
那浑蛋还活着
Son of a bitch is still alive.
-帅哥 -搞什么K？
- Hey, pretty. - What the...?
难不成你想尖叫吗？
What you gonna do, scream?
你怎么还活着？
How the hell are you still breathing?
你怎么把手接回去了？
What the hell'd you do to your hand?
轻一点K
Easy, easy.
我最近请人帮忙接回去的
I recently had some work done.
地图在哪里？
Where's the map?
轻一点K不在我身上
Easy, easy, easy. I don't have it.
-在哪里？ -我说过不在我身上
- Well, where is it? - I'm telling you, I don't have it.
-不在身上？ -你刚才在那，我们看见了
- Don't have it, huh? - You were there. We saw you.
已经不见了 叫你的狗离我远一点
It was gone. Why don't you keep your pooch away from me?
我就把一切告诉你
I'll tell you everything I know.
被那个小子拿走了
It's the kid. He has it.
我今天早上遇到他
I saw him this morning.
我需要帮忙，所以我们达成协议
I needed some help. We made a deal, all right?
他答应负责挖掘 我则告诉他地图的位置
He said that he would dig. I told him where we could get a map at.
什么小子？
What kid?
（伊利诺州芝加哥 州长官邸）
最佳策略就是静观其成
The best thing to do is nothing.
参议院这样就会让我当副总统？
That's how I'll get the U.s. Senate to confirm my vice-presidency?
-静观其成？ -让他们了解你能胜任
- Do nothing? - Shows them you can do the job.
等等，是我女儿打来的
Wait a minute. It's my daughter.
长官，我们得谈谈令嫒的事
Sir, we need to talk about your daughter.
她怎么了？
What about her?
媒体正大肆报导 福克斯河越狱的新闻
Well, the media is all over this Fox River situation.
我们认为你现在最好暂时疏离她K
We think it would be best if you could distance yourself from her...
你们有完没完？ 我付完保释金就离开
If I hear this one more time... I paid her bail. I walked away.
我已经疏离她了
I have distanced myself.
给我一分钟
Give me a minute.
爸，是我
Hey, Dad, it's me.
你有空的时候 我有些事想和你谈谈
When you get a chance, I really need to talk to you about some things.
事实上我有很多事要说
Actually, a lot of things.
最重要的是K
The most important one is that...
我必须向你道歉
...I owe you an apology.
我最近造成你很多困扰
I realize that I've made things difficult for you lately.
我想要负起全责
And I wanna take responsibility for that.
请回电给我，再见
Call me back. Bye.
-你好，我来早了，不过有带晚餐 -请进
- Hi. I know I'm early, but I brought dinner. - Come on in.
-你不是素食者吧？ -不是
- You're not a vegetarian, are you? - No.
关上就好
Just shut that behind you.
-介意让我收电邮吗？ -不会，拿去吧
- Do you mind if I check my e-mail? - No, not at all. Here.
-你真大方，谢谢 -没问题
- Oh, you're so kind. Thank you. - Absolutely.
（铁路无线上网）
（美国陆军）
（地点搜寻 开开牧场，1971年）
（地点，犹他州图尔）
-你有笔吗？ -有
- Do you happen to have a pen handy? - Yeah.
真的很谢谢 抱歉这么麻烦你
Thank you so much. I'm so sorry to bother you.
-我有铅笔和笔记本 -谢谢
- No, look, I have a little pencil and pad. - Thank you.
-先生K -什么事？
- Sir. Sir. - Yeah?
昔安站没有人叫雪莉
No sherry in Cheyenne.
你的车票不能使用
Your ticket is not valid for travel.
等等K一定是搞错了
Oh, well, hold on, now. That can't be right. That can't be right.
-借过一下 -好的
- Excuse me for a second. - Sure.
好吧，兄弟 我向你一五一十坦承
All right, now, listen, brother, I'm gonna give it to you straight up.
我真的K我现在身无分文
Seriously, I don't... I'm broke, okay?
我说的是实话
Now, that's the truth.
我不久前遇上了麻烦
Now, I just ran into some trouble a while back.
我现在很努力想振作起来 你懂吗？
I'm just trying to pull it all together now. You understand?
五分钟后 你可以把这些事告诉警方
Well, you can tell that to the authorities in about five minutes.
别这样，不需要通知警方K
Come on, brother, we don't have to get the authorities...
太迟了
It's too late.
他们已经在下一站等你
They're already waiting at the next stop.
这两位警员会陪你 直到下车为止
These guys here are gonna sit with you until we stop.
我了解K
I understand. I understand.
-嘿！ -这边
- Hey! - Come here.
-先生 -你不能进去那里
- Sir. - Hey, you can't go in there.
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness.
确认有人看到富兰克林
Okay, we've got a confirmed sighting on Franklin.
他在爱达荷州普雷斯顿 跳下行进间的火车
He jumped out of a moving train in Preston, Idaho.
芝加哥黑人到爱达荷州做什么？ 他一定是迷路了
What is a black man from Chicago doing in Idaho? He's gotta be lost.
富兰克林在爱达荷 包威在内布拉斯加
Franklin's in Preston, Bagwell's in Nebraska.
这两人从未跨越过密西西比
Both men have never been across the Mississippi.
要造访亲友吗？我可不认为
Visiting friends and family? I don't think so.
更何况他们不是前往南方边境
And not south of the border.
他们往西走，我们要查出原因
They're due west, and we need to know why.
下车
Out.
-怎么了？ -你说中间人往哪里去？
- What's going on? - Where'd you say Tweener was headed?
往大街去，他要去买铲子
Up on the main drag. He's supposed to find a shovel.
-进去 -不要K
- In. - No.
-不要K -进去
- No, no, no. - In.
你们会回来吧？一定要回来
You're coming back, right? You're coming back?
-会的 -两位
- Yep. - Hey, you guys.
嘿
Hey.
别这样，里面好热
Come on, man. I'm boiling up in here.
（伍德园艺行）
我开着越野车，速度飞快 我紧追在他后方
I was on my ATV and I was hauling ass. I was right on her tail.
我拿出枪，结果他跑上树
I pulled out my gun and... that bitch treed herself.
我一枪就把他打下来
And I brought her down in one shot.
-他有多重？ -上百磅
- What'd she weigh? - At least a hunny.
-应该有110磅 -有空来找我们
- Maybe 110. - Come on out and see us if you want.
-一定会很好玩 -好，我考虑一下
- It's gonna be a good time. - Yeah, I just might do that.
你打算挖什么？
Hey, now. What you digging?
我爷爷院子里的东西
Some stuff in my grandpa's yard.
我后面仓库有更大的，可以挖更深
I got a bigger one in the back if you're going deep.
不用，这支就好
No, this'll do.
你长得真眼熟
Damn it if I don't know you from somewhere.
也许我认识你爷爷
Maybe I know your grandpa.
不太可能，他一个月前才搬来
Doubt it, man. He moved here like a month ago so...
他叫什么名字？
What's his name?
他叫爷爷，可以吗？ 可以结帐了吗？
His name's Grandpa, all right? Can you just ring this up?
-我还有事要办 -当然，老兄
- I gotta get out of here. - Sure thing, fella.
我帮你结帐
I'll ring it up.
我马上结帐
I'll ring it right now.
我知道了，我在电视上看过你
I know where I've seen you. On TV.
你是福克斯河监狱的逃犯之一
You're one of them Fox River boys.
-你认错人了 -不，我没认错
- You got it wrong, man. - No, I think I got it right.
店关门了
We're closed.
抱歉
Sorry, bud.
我们今天提早关门
We're closing up early today.
等等，先不要走
Hey, hold on. Stay right there.
你跟你的伙伴完蛋了，浑蛋
You're going down just like your buddy, you son of a bitch.
那小子在哪里？
Where's the kid?
-他在哪里？ -他在后面
- Where's the kid? - He's back here.
起来
Get up.
硬汉，我们走
Come on, tough guy.
我们走
Let's go.
（内华达州，拉斯维加斯）
犸丽？宝贝，开门
Maricruz? Baby, open up.
是我K别怕
It's me. It's me, okay?
费南多，你来这里做什么？ 你不能来这里
Fernando, what are you doing here? You can't be here.
我知道，泰瑞莎 你妹妹在哪里？我要见她
I know. Where's your sister? I need to see her.
她和我爸妈在照相
She's getting her picture taken with my mom and dad.
-婚礼两点三十分就要举行 -我现在要见她
- The wedding's at 2:30. - I need to see her now.
-你快走吧 -她是我孩子的母亲，泰瑞莎
- You have to go. - She's the mother of my kid, Theresa.
拜托你
Please.
你不希望她嫁给赫特吧？ 对不对？
You don't want her to marry Hector, do you? Do you?
我去看能不能找她来
I'll go see if I can go get her.
-在里面等 -好
- Wait in here. - Okay.
-兰斯，我有事问你 -什么事？
- Lance, I got a question for you. - Yes?
你知道我的身份吗？
You know who I am?
我昨晚刚好看到新闻，所以知道
I happened to see the news last night, yes.
我不在乎，我也有不可告人的秘密
Hey, I don't care. I've got some skeletons in my closet too.
其中一个秘密还会穿裙子
One of whom wears a dress.
谢谢，感谢你不批判我
Thank you. I appreciate your lack of judgment.
依我来看，你没有做错事
From what I can tell, you didn't do anything wrong.
但这不关我的事，你不必跟我说
But it's none of my business, and you don't need to talk about it.
这整件事真是K
The whole thing just...
我不是故意让它发生的
I never meant for it to happen.
这个问题你不一定要回答
Okay, you do not need to answer this question.
你和那个男人真的有K？
But were you and that guy, like?
你说得对，我不想谈这件事
You're right, I don't wanna talk about it.
-你吃完了吗？ -对
- You're done? - Yeah.
他在逃亡，你会担心他吗？
Does it worry you that he's out there?
等我一下
Give me one second.
-爸 -莎拉，你好
- Dad. - Sara, hi.
我听到你的留言了
I got your message.
请进
Please, come in.
兰斯，这位是我的父亲弗兰克
Lance, this is my father, Frank.
-你好吗？ -爸，这是我的朋友兰斯
- How do you do? - Dad, this is my friend, Lance.
很荣幸见到你，我有投你一票
Pleasure to meet you, sir. And I voted for you.
谢谢，我很感激
Thank you. I appreciate that.
-莎拉，我可以先离开 -不用
- Sara, I can take off. - No need.
一下就好
Only take a minute.
我们进我的办公室谈，你别拘束
You step into my office. And you make yourself at home.
好
Sure.
这个K
So...
在我参加的计划中 我们谈到许多赎罪的事情
so in my program, we've been talking a lot about making amends.
我也思考了很多关于K
And I've been thinking a lot about...
关于我最近做的决定
About some of the choices I've made lately.
我知道我的行为影响到你
And I know that that affects you.
而我想向你道歉
And I wanted to tell you that I'm sorry.
-你不必向我道歉 -不，有必要
- Well, you don't have to say you're sorry. - Yeah, I do.
你一定很难理解我为何会这么做
And it must be hard to understand why I did it.
我没想到我会让这些人越狱
I had no idea that I was putting these guys back out on the street.
我以为这么做是救无辜的生命
I thought I was saving the life of an innocent man.
我知道我给你的 林克柏劳资料
And I know that you didn't read the information I gave you...
你并没有看，但是他是清白的
...on Lincoln Burrows, but he is innocent...
现在案子牵连的人 很多都丧命了
...and a lot of the people involved right now are dead.
抱歉，这不是我找你的用意
I'm sorry. This isn't why I called you.
我很好
I'm fine.
但是我很害怕
But I'm scared.
莎拉
Sara.
我会帮你度过难关
I'm gonna help you through this.
我们一起解决这件事
We're gonna get through this together.
-谢谢 -我向你保证
- Thank you. - I promise.
-凯勒曼 -我们做了你要的追踪
- Kellerman. - We ran that trace you requested,
-有何结果？ -电话是空号
- What'd you get? - The line is disconnected,
-那是谁的电话？ -没有人
- And whose was it? - Apparently no one,
-什么意思？ -那号码已经停用17年了
- What does that mean? - It's been out of service for 17 years,
费南多
Fernando.
-她在哪里？ -冷静一点K
- Where is she? - Now, calm down. Calm down.
她会来跟你谈的
She's gonna come down and talk to you.
她马上就来
She's on her way down right now.
你和我交情匪浅 我们是家人
You and I got history. We're family.
我尊重这点 所以我会让她自己决定
Out of respect for that, I'm gonna let her make her own decision.
-我一定要带她走 -犸丽自己会决定
- I'm not leaving without her. - That's for Maricruz to decide.
-你一直对她洗脑 -她是聪明的女孩
- You've been filling her head with this crap. - She's a smart girl.
我个人认为她不会想过逃亡的生活
I personally don't think she's gonna wanna live her life on the run.
-等着瞧吧 -你知道她不爱你
- We'll see. - You know she doesn't love you.
-别太早下定论 -不准你扶养我的小孩
- I don't wanna get into that right now. - You're not raising my kid.
这声音不太妙，表弟
That don't sound good, cuz.
-犸丽？宝贝？她在哪？ -你得快走
- Maricruz? Baby? Where is she? - You have to go.
-她在哪里？ -求求你，警察来了
- Where is she? - Please. They're coming.
你有告诉她我来了吗？有吗？
Did you tell her I was here? Did you?
犸丽
Maricruz.
我是曼宏
Mahone.
我马上过来
I'll be right down.
-曼宏先生 -东西在哪？
- Mr. Mahone. - Where are they?
我费尽心血才拿到这些药 行行好去看医生吧
I had a hard time getting my hands on these. Be easier to go to a doctor.
你需要镇定的药
You need something to calm your nerves.
医生会记录，所以我才和你交易
Doctors take notes. That's why I have a deal with you.
看之前的情况 我还以为我们的交易结束了
The way things have been going, I thought our deal was over.
-你不问席尔斯的消息了 -那部份已经结束了
- You don't ask me about shales no more. - That part is over.
那案子我不需要线人
I no longer need an informant on the case.
我以为你一心只想抓到他
I thought that's all you cared about, was finding him.
-不可能全都抓到 -我可以去打听K
- Can't get them all. - I can keep an ear out on the street...
每30天给我1500毫克 咪达唑仑，我只需要这些
Midazolam, 1500 milligrams every 30 days. That's all I want from you.
达成共识了吗？
We understand each other?
你不打算付钱？
You gonna pay me for it?
拿去
Right there.
-你们来这做什么？ -来拯救你，兄弟
- What are you doing here? - We had to come for you, buddy.
-你们怎么知道我在这里？ -茶包说的
- How'd you know? - T-Bag.
把地图交出来
Hand over the map.
-什么？ -地图
- What? - The map.
交出来
Hand it over.
他说在我身上？
He told you I had it?
（屋子、谷仓）
（地窖、水井）
我们现在就把问题解决
We are gonna sort this out right now.
告诉我那不是地图
Tell me that's not what I know it is.
是地图没错，但别担心
It is. But don't worry.
被我毁掉前 我已经深深记在脑海里了
Before I destroyed it, I committed it to my photographic memory.
你这大骗子说的话 我很难相信
Coming from a compulsive liar, I find that hard to believe.
原本我想纹在身上 可是时间不够
I'd have tattooed it to my body, but I didn't have the time.
替无期徒刑犯搜身时 绝对别忘了检查零钱包
Whenever you strip-search a lifer, you should always check his coin purse.
告诉我们钱在哪里
Tell us where the money is.
我们不必暴力相向，好吗？
Now, let's not dissolve into threats, all right?
我要大发慈悲 提出一项对双方都有利的建议
I'm gonna take the high road here. Suggest a mutually beneficial arrangement.
我知道地点
I have the information.
你们则有体力
You have the manual requirements...
可以挖出威莫兰的钱财
...necessary to unearth Westmoreland's buried booty.
-我们是伙伴 -为什么？
- We're partners. - And why is that?
因为就目前来看 我就是你们的地图
Because as of this moment, I'm your map.
之后我们四人平分，对吗？
So then, yo, we split it four ways, right?
错，进去
Wrong. Get in.
你不值150万
You're not worth 1.5.
-进去 -好啦
- Get in. - Okay.
（犹他州，卡什郡）
不好意思，你有事吗？
Excuse me. Can I help you?
有，抱歉K
Oh, yeah, sorry. Yeah.
天气好热
It's hot.
我想请问 你的野营旅游车要卖多少钱？
I was really wondering how much you're selling your RV for.
-你应该买不起 -你开个价钱嘛
- Probably out of your price range. - Come on. Give me a shot.
四万美金
Forty thousand dollars.
（求售）
不如这样
Look, I tell you what.
我几天后再来，好吗？
I'll be back in a couple of days, okay?
我没办法帮你预留
I can't hold it for you.
我一定回来
I said I'll be back.
付现金给你
With cash.
（内华达州，梅斯基特）
（内华达与犹他州边境一里处）
机车很棒
Nice bike.
两点半就要举行婚礼，费南多
The wedding's at 2:30, Fernando,
确定费南多苏克的位置
We just got confirmation on Fernando sucre.
他在大约两点时 出现在拉斯维加斯
He was in Las Vegas around 2.
之后一名加油站员工
Then a gas station attendant...
在梅斯基特 目击一名符合描述的机车骑士
...spotted a guy on a bike matching his description in Mesquite...
时间是一小时后
...an hour later.
他在西部 跟包威和富兰克林一样
Out west. Just like Bagwell and Franklin.
对，不过他往东走
Yeah, but he was heading east...
包威从内布拉斯加 走80号公路往西
...and Bagwell's in Nebraska on l-80 heading west...
富兰克林的火车也往西走 可是他跳下火车往K
...and Franklin's train was heading west, but he jumped off to the...
-知道迪比库柏是谁吗？ -知道，那个劫机犯
- You know D.B. Cooper? - Yeah, the hijacker.
-可是他失踪了 -对，但人不会消失
- But he was never found. - But he's gotta be somewhere.
有人在波特兰劫机 然后在西北太平洋跳机
Someone hijacked that plane in Portland and jumped out over the Pacific Northwest...
两天后在亚利桑那州比斯比 有人被逮捕
...and someone was arrested two days later in Bisbee, Arizona.
-不是同一个人 -是同一个人
- Not the same guy. - Same guy.
这个人在Q湖城附近的K
Same guy who was treated for a broken knee...
免费诊所治疗膝盖骨折
...at a free clinic somewhere around salt Lake City.
这个人的雪佛兰 在边境附近十里处故障
Same guy whose Nova blew a head gasket 10 miles short of the border.
这个人差一点偷车逃逸
Same guy who almost got away with a stolen car...
可是他在比斯比撞死一名女子
...but he ran a woman down in Bisbee.
罪名是驾车过失杀人
Vehicular manslaughter.
他以查理威莫兰的名字 被逮捕并监禁
Arrested and booked as Charles Westmoreland.
可是钱不在他身上
But he didn't have the money on him.
这代表K
Which means...
他在途中把钱藏了起来
...he got rid of it somewhere along the way.
-确定了吗？你自己想出来的？ -不，是史柯菲
- This is fact? You figured all this out? - No, scofield did.
所以他才会带着老头越狱 这笔钱在犹他州
That's why he was bringing the old man. The money's in Utah.
所有人都要去抢钱
And they're all going to get it.
你们知道吗？泰国有个黑市
You know, in Thailand, they got a black market...
任何手术都可以帮你做 即使是手掌移植也可以
...where you can get any surgery you need, even a hand transplant.
你很变态，你知道吗？
You're sick, you know that?
继续走，寐肪驮谇懊娓浇
Keep going. The turnoff's just up here somewhere.
在绵羊路前方还是后方？
Before or after sheep Road?
西奥多，怎么了？忘了吗？
What's the matter? Did you forget?
绵羊路这么特别 我怎么会忘，在后方
How could I forget a road called sheep? It's after.
我们再度合作 你们不感到温馨吗？
Don't you feel all warm inside now that we're working together?
我们不是合作 你只是出一臂之力
We aren't working together. You're just here to lend a hand.
等等，慢下来，你看 那里，后面那条小路
Wait, wait, slow down. That was it. That little bitty road right back there.
离这里有多远？
How far is it from here?
四分之一里 如果我没记错地图比例的话
A quarter mile, if I remember the scale properly.
我们走吧
Let's start walking.
（私人土地，勿擅自进入）
-弗兰克 -我快准备好了
- Frank? - Yeah, I'm almost ready.
-你说飞机几点起飞？ -八点
- What time did you say the flight was? - Eight.
听着，我非常希望你得到提名 但你要有心理准备
Listen, I hope you get this nomination more than anyone, but be prepared.
柏劳案可能冲击很大
This Burrows thing may steamroll.
-你不是说等锋头过去就好？ -问题是新闻一个接一个出现
- Well, we'll wait it out, just like you said. - Problem is too many headlines.
他的律师尼克沙弗林已经死了
His lawyer, Nick savrinn, is already dead.
他的儿子因两项谋杀罪 正等待受审
His kid's awaiting trial for double homicide...
而他的主要律师目前失踪
...and now his lead counsel is classified as missing.
她是失踪还是死了？
Well, is she missing or is she dead?
我想在你去华府前 先知会你一声
I just thought you should know before you go to Washington.
布鲁斯，这些事情都有关联吗？
Bruce, is there something connecting all of this?
你不要多过问对你比较好
It's probably best you don't ask a whole lot of questions.
（林克柏劳）
往哪走？
Where now?
就在前面
Right up there.
这座山丘是土地边界
The hill borders the property.
开开牧场就在山丘后面
The K.K. Is on the other side.
拿到钱我第一件要做的事
First thing I'm gonna do with the money:
-就是买双新鞋 -第二是买炸玉米饼
- Buy new shoes. - Second thing, tacos.
第三是冰凉的啤酒
Third thing, ice-cold beer.
第四是买牙膏
Fourth thing, a little toothpaste.
-我是曼宏 -您的车来了，长官
- Mahone. - Agent Mahone, your car's out front, sir,
-往犹他的飞机一小时后起飞 -我马上到，谢谢
- The flight to Utah leaves in an hour, - I'll be there. Thank you.
第九件事，要淋浴
Ninth thing, a shower.
-第十件事，好好睡一觉 -找家好旅馆，干净的床单
- Tenth thing, a good night's sleep. - A nice hotel. Clean sheets.
-你看，有划分土地的木桩 -肯定就在前面了
Look, stakes marking the property line. Should be dead ahead.
有看到地窖吗？
Can you see the silo?
浑蛋们在上面盖满房子
The bastards built over it.
地窖不见了
It's gone.